Clement Gendler

LinkedIn: /clement-gendler/ • clementgendler98@gmail.com • clementgendler.github.io • 914-584-3238

About

I take on challenges to meet business needs with an insightful data-driven approach. With experience in Data Analytics, Data Science, Healthcare, and AdTech, I'm an innovator that creatively solves complex problems to provide value for clients. Other passions I have besides working with big data are creative writing, exploring NYC, and listening to classic rock.

Skills

Technical: SQL, Python, Data Visualization (Looker, Tableau), Snowflake, Spark, Google BigQuery, R, Pandas, Numpy, Scikit-Learn, Keras, TensorFlow, Natural Language Processing, Git/GitHub, HTML/CSS, JavaScript, Java **Additional:** Spanish speaker (professional working proficiency), Microsoft Office (Excel, PowerPoint), Statistics

Professional Experience

Data Analyst Nov 2021 - Present

DeepIntent

New York, NY

- Builds SQL queries in Snowflake, Google BigQuery, and Spark to combine various data sets for ad hoc analyses
- Uses Looker to create dashboards, assemble models within LookML, and design custom data visualizations
- Provides data-driven, thoughtful reports across DeepIntent's product suite and client base using Statistics
- Develops innovative methodologies to derive and evaluate performance benchmarks, which are presented to clients
- Audits and identifies improvement opportunities in our Patient Modeled Audiences, causing key KPIs to increase
- Creates and maintains thorough documentation as the point of contact for dashboard report management

Platform Production Analyst, Crossix Analytics

Jan 2021 - Nov 2021

Veeva Systems

New York, NY

- Produced and managed DIFA HCP Site, a platform for informing, measuring, and optimizing healthcare marketing
- Used SQL, Python, Excel, Spark, a logic-based proprietary language, and data visualization tools to produce monthly DIFA deliverables that track site visitation and web analytics
- Analyzed root causes and data anomalies while monitoring and troubleshooting analysis execution
- Automated, planned, and improved internal processes through collaboration with the Engineering team
- Handled client inquiries related to data and DIFA methodology by providing insight to the Client Services team

Data Science Fellow Aug 2020 - Nov 2020

General Assembly

New York, NY

- Completed 480-hour immersive course in python programming and data science
- Solved real-world problems by applying data collection, cleaning, visualization, analysis, modeling, as well as machine learning and deep learning techniques to large data sets
- Predicted a Chess game's outcome using only moves played with LSTM and GRU neural networks
- Analyzed and classified 5,000 Reddit posts using Natural Language Processing

Education

New York University

- B.A. in Economics, Class of 2020, New York, NY
- Buenos Aires Study Abroad August 2017 December 2017

Udemy

- The Complete Google BigQuery Masterclass: Beginner to Expert, Certificate of Completion, October 2022
- Advanced SQL: The Ultimate Guide, Certificate of Completion, December 2022